Finding Aid for the Kathleen Thompson Norris Papers LSC.0946
UCLA Library Special Collections
Kathleen Thompson Norris papers
1924-1939
UCLA Library Special Collections
Norris, Kathleen Thompson
LSC.0946
4.0 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Kathleen Thompson (1880-1966) was a author who wrote short stories and contributed to magazines. Her published works include: Mother (1911), The Callahans and the Murphys (1924), The foolish virgin (1928), Bread into roses (1937), The Venables (1941), and Family gathering (1959). The collection consists of Norris' literary manuscripts, some with holographic alterations.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Friends of the UCLA Library, purchase, 1967 & 1972.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942335083606533
Biography
Kathleen Thompson was born on July 16, 1880 in San Francisco, California; briefly attended UC Berkeley; married author Charles G. Norris in 1909; began writing short stories in 1910, and contributed to magazines; published works include: Mother (1911), Josslyn's wife (1918), The Callahans and the Murphys (1924), The foolish virgin (1928), My San Francisco (1932), Bread into roses (1937), The Venables (1941), Through a glass darkly (1957), and Family gathering (1959); she died on January 18, 1966.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of literary manuscripts of novelist Kathleen Thompson Norris, some with holographic alterations.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Belle mère, Walls of gold (Box 1).
Lost sunrise, Angel in the house, The runaways (Box 2).
The black Flemings, Bread into roses, Three men and Diana (Box 3).
Maiden voyage, American Flaggs (Box 4).
Rose of the world, Barberry bush (Box 5).
Irish eyes, Red silence, Shining windows (Box 6).
Irish eyes (another typescript), Secret marriage, Beauty and the beast (part 3) (Box 7).
Dedications (Box 8).
Items Removed from Collection
Norris, Kathleen (Thompson), 1880-1966. Dedications. Berkeley: Printed by Wilder & Ellen Bentley for Charles G. Norris, 1936. Page proofs, 46pp., hand numbered. With typescript title page. Wrapped in first gathering of Portsmouth Plaza. The Cradle Of San Francisco by Catherine Coffin Phillips, San Francisco: Printed by John Henry Nash, 1932 [Removed to Jake Zeitlin Graphic Arts Ephemera Collection (Collection 2000). Available at Department of Special Collections, UCLA.].
Related Material
Charles Gilman Norris Papers (Collection 945). Available at UCLA Library Special Collections.
Manuscripts for publication; Women novelists, American -- California, Northern -- Archives.; Norris, Kathleen Thompson -- Archives
- Belle Mere, 1931.; Carbon, 368pp. Holographic alterations throughout. (Box 1)
- Walls Of Gold, 1933.; Two apparently identical carbons, 368pp. each. (Agent's copies?). (Box 1)
- Lost Sunrise, 1939.; Original typescript, 391pp. With many holographic alterations. (Box 2)
- Angel In The House, 1933.; Original typescript, 323pp. Many holographic alterations. (Box 2)
- The Runaways, 1939.; Typescript 385pp. (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents note
  Apparently for submission to a motion picture company. Title bears superscription in ink, To be published as a serial in Colliers commencing July 1938 and thereafter as a novel by Doubleday Doran.
- The Black Flemings, 1926.; Final carbon. 347pp. (Box 3)
- Bread Into Roses, 1937.; Carbon, 385pp. Some holographic corrections. (Box 3)
- Three Men And Diana, 1934.; Revised typescript, 376pp. With many holographic and typed revisions. (Box 3)
- Maiden Voyage, 1934.; Original typescript. 378pp. (Box 4)
- American Flaggs, 1936.; Typescript, 408pp., with typed and holographic corrections and additions throughout. (Box 4)
- Rose Of The World, 1924.; Final carbon, 409pp. (Box 5)
- Barberry Bush, 1927.; Final carbon, 539pp. (Box 5)
- Irish Eyes, n.d.; Typescript, 247pp., and carbon on onion skin, 235pp. Different typing, both complete. (Box 6)
- Red Silence, 1929.; Final carbon, 369pp. (Box 6)
- Shining Windows., Typescript. 314pp. (Box 6)
- Irish Eyes., Typescript. 205pp. (Box 7)
- Secret Marriage., Typescript. 283pp. (Box 7)
- Beauty And The Beast., Part 3. Typescript (carbon) 391pp. (Box 7)